# **FUNGAI.M. MANGONDOZA**

www.marshallfungai.github.io | +90 54 8876 1289 | fmarshall.m@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/fmarshallm



#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Individual with a solid foundation as a full stack application developer. Embarking on a balance into the field of cybersecurity and software development. Over the past 8+ years, I have honed my skills in software development, gaining expertise in front-end and back-end technologies.

I am a quick learner and able to adapt to new technologies easily and an observant team player who complements the best efforts of everyone.

To find out more about the projects undertaken outside working experience, visit https://github.com/marshallfungai.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack developer (Remote)

June 2021 – Present

Photon Organization – Johannesburg Gauteng, South Africa

Energy company specializing in solar installations

- Develop inhouse software for management,
- Manage and coordinate system architecture,
- Role in application security
- Use of technologies Javascript, php, mysql, flutter and python
- Third party software integration
- Secondary role, in assisting server and network management

#### Software Developer (Full Time)

NETHOUSE NETWORKS | North Cyprus - Nicosia (www.nethouse.net)

The largest ISP provider in North Cyprus

- Develop modern front-end interfaces,
- Using react, redux, php and react-native
- Flutter (dart framework) for beautiful and fast mobile app development
- Partly red-teaming to test web application security

Full Stack Developer (Full Time)

November 2015 - September 2019

October 2019 - February 2021

## ATA BİLİŞİM | North Cyprus – Nicosia (www.atabilisim.pro)

A digital agency specializing in brand management and social media marketing.

- Website design
- API integration and data management.
- Joomla/Wordpress theme development and customization, and plugin development
- Search Engine Optimizations (SEO)
- Web app maintenance and upgrade
- Security reviews and user management
- Additional responsibilities include photoshop designs for social media clients.

Data Entry (Part-time) 4 month Contract

ASEL GRP OF COMPANIES | North Cyprus – Sanayi Bogesi/Industrial Complex

Performed data entry clerical tasks for the company's micro-database system (custom database for their products).

#### Junior Web Developer (Temporary)

May 2015 - October 2015

INNOVIA DIGITAL | North Cyprus – Nicosia (www.innoviadigital.com)

 Worked as a third hand in multiple projects, debugging apps, design implementation of some functions and also making scripts to accomplish repetitive tasks

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS MATRIX**

DATABASES AND STORAGE	Years of Experience	Level (1 - 10)
MySQL, PostgreSQL	4 years and 2 years respectively	7
Google FireBase, RADIS	5 years	6
MongoDB	2 years	3
LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES	Years of Experience	Level (1 - 10)
<ul> <li>ES5, ES6, ES7, Jquery, PHP, React Native, React, Express JS (NodeJS), Flutter(DART), HTML, CSS3,</li> </ul>	8 Years for web technologies, 3 Years for the mobile technologies	8
Bash, Python, Laravel, Typescript, JWT	4 Years	7
AngularJS,	2 years	4
OPERATING SYSTEMS, TOOLS AND CONFIGURATIONS	Years of Experience	Level (1 - 10)
<ul> <li>Linux Configurations, GIT, Vagrant</li> <li>Google Analytics, Search Engine Optimization(SEO),</li> <li>Cloud Deployment(Digital Ocean), Wordpress theme and plugin development,</li> </ul>	8 years	8
OpenAl Integration, Open Source LLM integration	1 year	6
<ul> <li>Docker/Kubernetes</li> </ul>	1 year	3
CYBERSECURITY AND NETWORKING		
SAST/DAST concepts	3 Years	7
Web Penetration testing, Security Reporting, Risk Management,	2 Years	5
Endpoint Security, Disaster Recovery,	1 Year	4

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Cyber Threat Management CISCO ACADEMY

Issued by IBM

Cisco verifies the earner of this badge successfully completed the Cyber Threat Management course. The holder of this student-level credential is familiar with cybersecurity policies and governance to ensure an organization complies with ethics standards and legal and regulatory frameworks. They understand how to do a network vulnerability assessment and create a risk management plan, as well as post-incident response.

https://www.credly.com/badges/a58063eb-eef1-486e-beab-654ca469daae/public\_url

# **Artificial Intelligence Intro**

Issued by IBM

Through self-paced learning, this badge earner has displayed an understanding of topics such as Artificial Intelligence, Augmented Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Natural Language Processing.

https://www.credly.com/badges/a7b398fc-dcf9-42f5-bb6c-c5e2bbcaa858?source=linked in profile

Cloud Intro IBM

Issued by IBM

Through self-paced learning, this badge earner has displayed an understanding of topics such as cloud computing, cloud, IaaS, PaaS, SaaS, Hybrid Cloud, Private Cloud, data storage, and flexible infrastructure.

https://www.credly.com/badges/74fe3536-bff3-42e5-9f3f-f66a6b8a45c7?source=linked in profile

# **PROJECTS**

Dradis Framework dashboard Photon Organization

A inhouse security dashboard for Photon Organization. It is a dashboard which helps in collecting and reporting security issues. Worked with the different skilled individuals to meet all software development cycle targets. Early development version on github as a concept.

https://github.com/marshallfungai/dradis-ce

### **Nethouse and Kibrisonline Mobile Application**

Worked as the team lead to create 2 mobile apps for the 2 sister ISP companies. For IOS and Android using flutter.

www.nethouse.net

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=netonline.kibrisonline.kibrisonline hesabim app

# **Nethouse Networks Online Dashboard and Website**

Worked closely with a great team to develop the ISP customer dashboard and also the website

www.online.nethouse.net

#### **Skyborne Travel Agency**

Travel booking website built on Laravel and MySQL. I did the setup and continue maintenance work.

https://skybornetravel.com

Native-News-App

### **IVF Medical App**

https://github.com/marshallfungai/ivf-medical-app

 $\label{lem:medical app proposal for IVF hospitals to tackle the decline of walk in customers across the globe. \\$ 

Created in flutter it will also come with as assisted Laravel dashboard.

www.github.com/marshallfungai/React-

**React Native News App** 

News app created with react native using an API from "www.newsapi.org". An experimental base code for use with News website i.e. Wordpress sites broadcast API endpoints for posts, which can be news posts.

www.github.com/marshallfungai/Rent-A-CAR\_PhoneApp

#### **Rental Mobile App**

This app is using ionic framework. Its purpose is to pull available vehicles from a custom API to the client's mobile phone so as to keep them updated. And if certain vehicle is booked or already rented the customer will be notified.

#### **Laravel Article API**

https://github.com/marshallfungai/LAREVEL-CRUD-API

This was a base code for an API project based on Laravel, a php framework. The repo only contains the API code.

#### **Chat App**

www.github.com/marshallfungai/angular 2-node-socket-io-chat-app

Chat App built using Angular 2 and Node (Socket.io)

#### **EDUCATION**

# Ingressive For Good Cybersecurity Scholarship

2023

Virtual – Cisco Academy

#### **Core Courses:**

- Introduction to Cybersecurity from Cisco Networking Academy
- Cyber Threat Management from SkillsForAll,
- Network Defense from SkillsForAll

- Cybersecurity Essentials from Cisco Networking Academy,
- Cloud Security from Cisco Networking Academy,
- Endpoint Security from SkillsForAll

# Bachelor of Science in Applied Sciences (Management Information Systems): CGPA - 2.90/4.00

2014

Eastern Mediterranean University - North Cyprus

### **Core Courses:**

- Data Structures & Applications
- Internet/Web programming 1(client & Server side)
- Algorithms and Programming ,
- Structured Programming,
- Operating Systems

- Computer Networks,
- Database Management Systems ( oracle -SQL) (PL/SQL), ,
- Database Programming
- Java Programming
- Object Oriented Programming,

# Cambridge GCE Advance Level: Business studies, Accounting, Economics

2009

Jameson High School

#### **LANGUAGES**

 English – speak fluently and read/write with high proficiency Turkish –speak, read, and write with basic competence